Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
You ever think about dying?
Yeah you?
Yeah some.
You think there's a heaven?
Yeah. Don't you?
I don't know
yeah, maybe.
You think you can believe there's a
heaven if you don't believe in hell?
I guess you can believe what you want to.
This ranch has been in my family
as long as anyone can remember.
My granddaddy used to tell
me this was heaven on earth,
just like his granddaddy used to tell him.
Everything's changed now since he died.
- I appreciate you lightin' them candles.
- Como?
I as candelas I as velas
my mother?
Si
She was here?
All I ever wanted was to
live out there like he did,
work my own spread.
Can't imagine no better life.
I've come fo find out mama aims to sell it
says the oil company'd pay
three times what it's worth.
Mama lives in San anfonio
now with her new husband.
May the lord bless and keep you.
She wanits fo be in live theater
as your granddaddy's only child,
your mother inherits outright.
It's her property now. She can
do whatever she wants with it
I don't have any say-so?
What about my father?
They're divorced.
You could talk to her.
- You're a lawyer.
- Well, I have talked to her, but...
It's a sorry piece of business, but, son,
not everybody thinks that life
on a cattle ranch in west Texas
is the second best thing
to dyin' and goin' to heaven.
She don't wanna live out there, that's all.
If it was a payin' proposition,
that'd be one thing, but it ain't.
It could be I could run it
it's his own damn fault.
Your father signed every piece of
paper she set in front of him,
never lifted a hand to save himself
- I told him to get a lawyer, hell, I begged him.
- Well
I'm sorry not to have no
better news for you, son,
but some things in this world
can't be helped,
and I believe this is probably one of 'em.
She went back to San Antonio.
Don't call her "she"
mama
you know I thought the world
of that old man, don't you?
Yeah
don't go crying on me now.
- I ain't.
- Well, don't.
I ain't
what do you think I should do?
I don't think there's much you can do.
Will you talk to her?
I can't talk to her
you could talk to her.
I ast conversation I had with her
was in San Diego, California, in 1942.
It ain't her fault
I ain't the same as I once was
I like to think I am,
but I ain't
you are, inside.
Inside, you are.
[T's hard fo watch the very people you came
from waste away right before your eyes.
And when the land 1s gone, foo,
I reckon there's nothing fo
stand on or stand for, either.
When do y'all have fo be out?
Closing's the first of June.
You could wait till then
what for?
Down in Mexico,
they got ranches so big,
you can't ride from one
end to the other in a week.
It ain't all fenced in and
sold off and played out.
Not down there.
You think they can't use
two more top hands?
Real cowboys?
Just like the old-time waddies
If I don't go, will you go anyways?
I'm already gone.
- Is that you, bud?
- You'd better hope so.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
They suspect anything?
No
- Let's go.
- Hang on a minute. I gotta pile all this stuff...
- Yonder goes the light.
- Damn!
You gonna be late for your own funeral.
He could just be gettin' him
a glass of milk or something.
He could just be loadin'
a shotgun. Yeah.
Lacey, shut up. Lacey.
There's been somebody following us.
- Somebody a-horseback?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Some kid that's a hell of a horse.
Ain't it, though?
You huntin' us?
No, I ain't huntin' you.
Then how come you followin' us?
I ain't. I'm goin' to langtry.
- I don't even know who y'all are.
- Where'd you get that horse?
- This is my horse.
- How old are you?
Sixteen.
You're a lyin' sack of spit!
- You don't know everything.
- I know you ain't no god damn 16.
What'd you do, run off?
What if I did?
- We could sell this horse in Mexico.
- Yeah you want to?
- I ain't diggin' no grave like we done that last one.
- Hell, that was your idea.
I was the one that said just
leave him for the buzzards.
Call it.
Heads
damn!
Let me have your rifle.
It ain't fair. You
shot the last three.
You go on then. You can owe me.
Better hold his horse.
Might not be gun-broke.
Y'all ain't never shot nobody.
What makes you think you wouldn't
be a good somebody to start with?
Y'all just funnin'.
I knowed it all along.
Who's huntin' you?
Nobody.
They're huntin' that horse
though, ain't they?
You ain't ridin' with us. Get
us throwed in the jailhouse.
- He belongs to me!
- Son, I don't give a shit who he belongs to,
but he damn sure don't belong to you.
Now, let's go, bud.
I thought he'd put up more of a argument.
We ain't seen the last of his skinny ass.
That's her, ain't it?
That's the god damn rio grande.
Just think,
over yonder's old Mexico.
Yep.
You reckon you wanna cross now?
Yeah you?
Yeah
maybe we'd better
rest these horses up first.
All right.
Shit.
I got a uneasy feelin' about
that little son of a bitch.
I do too.
He ain't as green as he looks, neither.
There won't nobody be huntin" me in Mexico.
- That all depends on what you done.
- What's your name?
Jimmy blevins.
You got any grub?
No
You got any money?
You're just a deadhead.
Just tell me one thing,
what the hell would we
want you with us for?
'Cause I'm a American.
When'd you eat last?
Other day.
Your name ain't blivet, is it?
Blevins
you know what a blivet is?
No, what?
A blivet's 10 pounds of
shit in a 5-pound sack.
- Y'all ain't said what y'all's names was.
- I'm John Grady Cole.
This here's Lacey rawlins.
We're from San Angelo.
Where you from?
Uvalde county, near the sabinal river.
What made you light out
for Mexico, blevins?
Same reason as you.
What reason is that?
'Cause you know they'd go bowlegged
and blind findin' your ass down here.
There ain't nobody huntin' me.
I told that son of a bitch
he wasn't whuppin' me again,
- and he didn't.
- Your daddy?
No. My daddy never did
come back from the war.
Your stepdaddy.
Yeah
lord, I know what it's
like to get a beatin'.
You didn't shoot him, did you?
I would've, and he knowed it.
Suppose we want to trade
that horse off there
for one less likely to get us shot.
I ain't tradin' horses
we ain't no god damn wet nurses.
- Well, I can take care of myself.
- Sure, you can.
Hell, you're a regular
ol' desperado, ain't you?
I reckon you got your
own gun and everything.
Well, yeah, I got a gun.
What kind of a gun?
30-220 Colt
well, that's a rifle
cartridge. Let's see it.
Where'd you get a gun like this?
At the gettin' place.
You ever shot it?
- Yeah, I shot it.
- Can you hit anything with it?
Anything you want.
Bullshit
all right, let's go,
outlaw. Come on.
You ready, Annie oakley?
Waitin' on you.
God damn!
I et me see it
- let me see it.
- We better get goin'.
Come on. Give it to me.
You know what it looks like.
It's my wallet.
- Hey!
- Hoo!
I ook at this kid.
She got anything to drink?
Tiene algo que tomar?
Si
What is that?
Que es?
Sidra.
Cider.
I et's have three of 'em.
- Mande?
- Tres.
How much is it?
- Cuanto?
- Para todo?
- Si.
- Uno cincuenta.
That's like three cents
let your ol' dad buy it then.
He about dead-centered
your pocketbook, didn't he?
I want you to look at my
god damn driver's license.
And my pool hall card.
You won't need them down here
- look at this shit.
- Appreciate it.
Shot Betty ward right between the eyes.
What's she doing in there?
I didn't know you liked her.
What is this? Cactus
juice or somethin'?
I don't know
got a little kick to it, though, don't it?
I think it does
pretty daggone good.
Well, say it again.
Say my name again.
I know, Santiago.
Golly! What am I doing leaving
my hat on the bed. Shit!
That's what I'm gonna do.
You shouldn't have no more cider
Hey.
Shit.
Hoo. I'm drunker than shit.
Well, can you ride or not?
Hell, yeah, I can ride.
I was ridin' when I fell off.
I'm a regular buckaroo.
Certified damn bronc filly.
Just leave the son of a bitch to lay there.
Get on the horse and quit assing around.
It's fixin' to come a good one.
Come on.
We can't be out in this
well, where do you think you're gonna go?
Why can't you be out in it?
On account of the lightning.
Well, damn if you don't look
halfway sober all of a sudden.
You afraid of lightning?
It runs in the family.
My grandpa, he was killed in
West Virginia in a mine bucket.
It run all the way down
the hole to get him, 180 feet.
I got a great-uncle on my mother's
side, he was killed off a horse.
It didn't singe a hair off that horse,
but it killed him graveyard dead.
I got a cousin not four
years older than me.
He was struck by lightning
comin' back from his barn.
Melted the fillin's in his teeth
and soldered his jaw shut.
He's gone completely dipshit.
Man, I done been struck twice myself.
I completely deaf in this one ear.
I'm born for death by fire, man.
You better get away from
anything metal at all.
You don't know what it'd get you.
Spurs in your boots,
buttons on your shirt...
What do you intend to do?
Outride it
you can't outride a thunderstorm
what the hell is wrong with you?
Man, it's the only chance I got.
I knowed it from the first time I seen him,
that son of a bitch had a loose wing nut.
What the hell are you doin'?
Just settin' here
if this rain hits hard,
there's gonna be a river come
down through here like a train.
You thought about that?
You ain't never been struck by lightning.
You don't know what it's like.
You gonna get drowned settin' there.
Well, that's all right.
I ain't never been drowned before.
Well, I'll say no more.
Your horse is gone.
Yeah, I know.
I done been on foot
lookin' around this mornin'.
Where'd you find that boot?
On the ground.
Well, what do you aim to do?
I don't know
well, get your ass up
outta there. Let's go.
Got a spare shirt in my saddlebag.
You can put that on.
Appreciate it.
Rawlins is gonna pitch
a pure hissy when he sees you.
I don't give a shit.
There's my damn pistol.
Hold on hold on
keep ridin'. Good god almighty.
I ain't leavin' here till I get
my stuff back, my gun too.
There you go, listen at that.
Get us all shot dead for horse-stealin'.
Don't mean a god damn thing to him.
Hey, it ain't horse-stealin'.
It's my horse!
- Listen here, shit-for-brains...
- Y'all hush.
- Both of you.
- If it weren't for your buddy here...
And get over here and sit down.
We're gonna stick here
until about a hour before daylight.
Now, you gotta play this
exactly like we say.
If that don't satisfy you,
you tell us right now.
Yeah, okay.
All right.
You go on and get some sleep.
And no fire tonight.
Every dumb thing I ever done in my life,
there was a decision I made
before that got me into it.
It was never the dumb thing.
It was always some choice I made before it.
You understand what I'm sayin'?
Yeah, I think so.
Meanin' what?
Meanin', this is it.
This is our last chance, right now.
There won't be no other
time, I guarantee it.
Meaning, just leave him?
Yes, sir.
What if it was you?
I wouldn't leave you. You wouldn't
leave me. That ain't no argument.
You realize the fix he's in?
It's the fix he's put himself in.
I can't do it
well, if you can't, you can't.
I guess I knew what you'd say anyways.
No damn it
that little son of a bitch!
Hold up. Hold up. Let's listen.
You little son of a bitch.
Boys, they're comin'.
Cars or horses?
Horses. And there ain't no way
y'all can keep up with me.
Listen, I'll take the road. They'll follow
the dust since it's me they're huntin'.
Y'all get out in the woods.
I'll see y'all down the road.
He's right. Let's get
off this damn road.
You think they caught him?
I don't know
I'll say one thing for him, anyways.
What's that?
Little son of a bitch wouldn't stand
still for nobody hijacking his horse.
You got your boots on?
Yeah
all right.
You reckon they're friendly?
Shoot, I hope so.
- Buenos dias.
Buenos dias.
He said "maybe."
Gracias.
Tr =a 53 t
Hyah!
Did you see that little darlin'?
Watch it, Lacey.
Bring him over here.
Get in there.
Bueno
Hey, bud.
How long you reckon you'd
like to stay here?
About 100 years.
Now go to sleep.
Me alegro, mi jefe.
Consequiste El caballo?
There's Don Hector Rocha y villareal.
Owns this whole shebang,
one of the last great ranches in Mexico.
27.000 acres.
Flies his own plane back and
forth to Mexico City every week.
Manuel said this ranch'd
been in his family 170 years.
You reckon that was his
daughter we seen yesterday?
Yeah, I guess it was.
Let me go get my boots on.
I ooks like there's about 12 or 13 of them.
I make it 16.
Armando said the old man's got something
like 400 mustangs up on that mesa.
Damn
you think you and me could break
all 16 of 'em in four days?
Why four days?
You think we could do it?
You'd be about a wore-out-sum-buck,
I'll tell you that.
Yeah?
Yeah
we'll have a look at 'em
and go talk to Armando.
How you doin'?
I'm all right.
We mess this up, bud, it's gonna
be a long ride back to Texas.
- Ho.
- Give him some slack, bud.
- That's it.
- That's it
boy.
Take him, bud.
I'm gonna put a saddle on you right now.
Gracias.
Senores senores.
You tired?
Hector de la Rocha, y villareal.
John Grady Cole.
Armando says you know a lot about horses.
I been around 'em some
do you know what a criollo is?
Yes, sir. It's a
Argentine horse.
You're from Texas?
Yes, sir.
San Angelo?
Why are you here?
I just wanted to see the country, I reckon,
or we did.
- You and your friend.
- Yes, sir.
But you are the leader.
We don't have no leaders.
No, we're just buddies.
Of course.
I recently purchased a thoroughbred
stallion of excellent blood.
You gonna raise race horses?
No. Quarter horses.
I'm thinking of breeding my
stallion with my mustano mares.
What's your opinion on that?
Well, I've known it done.
There's been some good cow horses
sired out of thoroughbreds.
What importance do you place on the mare?
Same as a sire.
In my opinion.
Most breeders would place more
confidence in the stallion.
Yes, sir, they do.
But I agree with you.
And you rode all the way here from Texas?
Yes, sir.
You and your friend?
Just the two of you.
Yes, sir.
Just me and him.
Well, Mr. Cole,
would you like to see some horses?
Yes, sir.
It ain't like you is going off some place.
No. We'll still be
working together.
It's a good opportunity for you.
Hell, I'd do it.
They told me to come bunk in here.
I was gonna put my horse
in one of these stalls.
Well, I guess we can talk later.
Gracias.
That's your mare, right there.
Look at the eye on her.
She's not as big as the other one,
but that's your mare right there.
Looks like some of 'em
got their hats on, bud.
I figure you just must be ready to
cry yourself to sleep every night.
She's probably used to datin' guys got
their own airplanes, let alone cars.
- You're probably right.
- Well, I'm glad to hear you sav it.
It don't change nothing, though, does it?
Con permiso.
- Hi.
- Hola.
Hola
- como estas?
- Muy bien.
My name is John Grady Cole.
My name is Alejandra.
I know
I hoped that you would come.
I come because I...
I thought you'd be here.
I know
My granddaddy lived his
whole life on that ranch,
seventy-four years.
Seemed there could hardly
be one without the other.
Well
I guess country lasts forever.
People ain't but for a little while.
And how will you live now?
Where will your home be?
What's wrong?
I dreamed about you last night.
What'd you dream about?
Someday I may tell you,
but not tonight.
I have something in my nose?
No. I have something in my nose.
Yo y solo yo.
A hell of a horse.
Hola
I want to ride him
what?
when?
Now
- I want to ride him now.
- Well, he don't have a saddle on.
I know
well, I don't think the patron
would want me to give him to
you without a saddle on him.
Your father.
- Get down.
- You sure about this?
Yes. Hurry.
Well, what do you aim
to do with your horse?
I want you to take him
back to the barn for me.
Somebody's gonna see me.
Fixin' to get me in trouble.
You are in trouble
I am senorita alfonsa.
I'm John Grady Cole.
I'm happy that you have come.
Alejandra will be in Mexico City
with her mother for two weeks,
then she'll be here for the summer.
Alejandra and I disagree strongly.
In fact I
she's so much like me at that age
that I seem, at times, to be
struggling with my own past self.
So, you see, I cannot help but
be sympathetic to Alejandra.
But I won't have her unhappy.
I won't have her spoken ill of
or gossiped about.
I know what that is.
It is not proper for you to be
seen riding in campo together
without supervision.
I considered whether to speak
to my niece about it,
but I
I've decided not to
what do you want me to do?
I want you to be considerate
of a young girl's reputation.
I never meant not to be
I believe you.
But, you see,
this is another country.
Here, a woman's reputation is all she has.
There's no forgiveness for women.
A man may lose his honor
and regain it again,
but a woman cannot
I guess I'd have to say
that that don't seem right.
It's not a matter of right.
It's a matter of who must say,
and, in this matter,
I get to say.
Quien es”?
Ljn momento.
What is it?
You're gonna wake Esteban.
Then invite me in.
What did she say to you, my aunt?
What? You wanna sit down?
Go on.
What did she say to you?
Didn't she tell you what she said to me?
Of course she did.
What did she say?
She said she didn't want
me bein' seen with you in the campo.
And you agreed?
You are afraid of her.
No
Just like everyone else.
It ain't like that
I hate the way she treats me.
I thought you were my friend.
You tell me what you want me to do.
I'll do anything you say.
Me quieres?
Si
See you after a while.
Look, I know the old man likes you.
That don't mean he's gonna set still
for you courtin' his daughter.
Yeah, I know.
- Well, I don't see you holdin' no aces, bud.
- Yeah.
What I see is you fixin' to get us
fired and throwed off this place.
Take it easy, bud!
Pero no me quiero ir!
What's this all about, partner?
Do you understand "shut up"?
I ain't above whippin' your ass, you know.
Don't you think if we're gonna
get out of this jackpot,
we might better start thinking about
how to get out of it together?
What? The way we got in it?
You think it was Rocha?
You think he sold us down the river?
I tried to reason with you.
I tried any number of times.
I know I know
some things ain't reasonable.
Look, I'm the same man
you crossed that river with.
How I was is how I am
and all I know to do is stick.
I don't believe in signing on
just until it quits suiting you.
You either stick or you quit.
And I wouldn't quit you,
I don't care what you done.
That's about all I got to say.
I never quit you.
All right.
Hey, y'all.
God help me.
How long you been in here?
I don't know. A long time.
At least a month
you told 'em to hunt us, didn't you?
Nah. I wouldn't
do nothin' like that.
Bullshit
they wouldn't be hunting us
if they got that horse back.
- He done something.
- It was my damn horse. My gun too.
- What'd you do?
- I didn't do nothin' nobody else wouldn't have.
- Did you come back here?
- Damn right I come back here.
Jesus. God. What'd you do?
He said he killed three men.
That's a damn lie
cuidado con El bote.
Don't step in the bucket.
We're dead we're dead men.
I knew it'd come to this. I knew it
from the first moment I seen him.
- Don't start that. It's not gonna help anything.
- Ain't but one of 'em died.
Tell me what happened.
Well, I got me a job on this farm.
Saved me up some money.
Then I rode back here to get my pistol.
And I seen it sticking
in some bitch's belt,
- so I just went up behind him and grabbed it.
- And shot him?
Well, he come at me.
What choice did I have?
What choice
time I got back to the spring
where my horse was at,
they done all caught back up with me.
An old boy, I shot off his horse.
He throwed down on me with a shotgun.
A rurale? Did you
shoot a rurale?
Yeah
dead?
what do you think they mean to do with you?
Send me to the penitentiary, I reckon.
You ain't gonna be that lucky.
Well, I'm too young to hang.
- They'll lie about your age for you.
- Don't listen to him.
There ain't no capital
punishment in this country.
You knew they were comin'
huntin' us, didn't you?
What was I supposed to do,
send you a telegram?
What happened to your feet?
They busted the hell out of 'em.
They didn't give you no
bandage or nothin' like that?
No
Shit.
Vamonos. You tell 'em whatever
they want to hear, bud.
It won't make a diff
what'd you tell 'em?
I told 'em we was murderers and
horse thieves. You will too.
Your friend fold us everything.
Better that you do the same,
and that way you avoid some trouble.
You had no right to beat up on that boy.
We don't know nothin' about blevins.
He asked to ride with us, that's all.
We don't know nothin' about that horse
horse got away from me in the thunderstorm
and then showed up here. And that's
when all the trouble started.
We've been working for senor Rocha going
on three months down in la purisima.
He went down there and
told them a bunch of lies.
Lacey rawlins' as good a boy as
ever's come out of Tom green county.
Is that the criminal Smith's?
The name ain't Smith, it's rawlins.
And he ain't a criminal.
I grew up with him.
The assassin blevins,
he did not have any documents.
He lost his clothes
he lost his clothes?
He has no feathers.
He what?
I wouldn't know anything about that.
That don't interest me.
Why does he come over here
and steal the horses?
- It was his horse.
- No, it's not his horse.
Well, you have it your own ignorant way.
Como?
As far as I know, that horse is his horse.
He had it with him in Texas,
and I know he brought it down to Mexico,
'cause I seen him ride it across the river.
That is not the facts.
We can make the truth here
or we can lose it here
but in three days, you're going
to be going to saltillo.
And then it's gonna
be too late for the truth.
Too late,
because you're gonna be
in the hands of other peoples.
Who's to say what the
truth is gonna be then?
And then you're gonna think about this day,
and you're going to blame yourself.
There ain't but one truth
the truth is what happened.
It ain't what come out of somebody's mouth.
The people in this town
are very quiet people.
Very quiet people all the time.
And then comes this assassin blevins,
and he kills everybody
and steals their horses.
Why does he do this?
Was he a good, quiet boy, that
he'd never do no harm to nobody?
And then he comes over here
and does something like that?
Is that what happened?
No
No, that's not what happened.
That's not the truth.
The truth is that he was
always the other kind of boy.
He was never a quiet boy.
He was always the other kind.
What happened?
Nothing.
I think we're going to saltillo.
What's in saltillo?
Penitentiary.
I think he wants to make
some kind of deal with us.
What kind of a deal?
Keep quiet.
That kind of a deal
keep quiet about what?
About blevins
about what about blevins?
I think they aim to kill him.
I think they aim to kill blevins.
Boys?
This is gonna be a long trip.
The old man said it was gonna take all day.
I asked him. He said
it was gonna take all day.
What's here?
What do we do here?
Take a leak, I reckon.
Against this wall.
What are they gonna do?
Vamos vamos.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Let go of me, damn it!
Vamos vamos wait a minute wait a minute
- let go of me!
- Vvamos.
Vamonos
This man came fo me
don't go to this man.
He came fo me fo talk with me about justice
and how his own brother had died at
the hands of the assassin blevins.
Then when it came time to do justice...
- Vamonos.
- He could nof shoot
he was like a woman.
A man cannot go out fo do something
and then not do if
no. A man does not
change his mind.
That's always been my way in this world.
- You didn't have to kill him.
- Como?
You could've just walked
him back to the truck.
You don't know nothin'
see, in my country, we don't
have death for criminals.
So monies have to be paid,
and arrangements have to be made.
I tell you this because
you're going to have to be making
“arrangement” with these peoples.
We don't have no money.
Cucaracha.
And here we have a boss, El jefe.
Everybody pays him.
Everybody does what he says.
I don't have any money.
We ain't fixin' to make any arrangements.
Excuse me, but you will.
And I'm telling you this
because I like you.
You cannot stay here.
You stay here, you're gonna die.
And then comes other problems.
The paperwork is lost.
People cannot be found.
Who's to say you're really here?
Some crazy people can
say that god is here...
But god is not here.
Everybody knows that god is not here.
I never dreamed there
was such a place as this.
I guess there's probably every
kind of place you could think of.
They're gonna kill us.
Don't let 'em think
they ain't gonna have to.
They either kill us or let us be.
Only way to get by in a place like this
is go about your business.
Don't act scared
Where you goin'?
I don't know, bud.
What is it?
A knife. A good one.
What's it like to be dead?
It ain't like nothin' at all
Yes, sir, you're a good healer.
Fast
you been doin' any doctorin'
on a boy named Lacey rawlins?
I'll send you some soap, some towels,
so you can wash up?
Adios
You don't know a Lacey rawlins?
You are fortunate boys.
Fortunate boys.
Where's rawlins?
He wait outside for you.
Right now?
Yes now.
Where we goin'?
You're going away.
You're going to your house.
Now?
Now
thought you died.
I thought you had.
Why ain't we dead?
She paid us out.
"Ei" senora?
The aunt yeah
why?
I don't know
It's got to do with that girl, don't it?
I expect it does.
You goin' back down there, ain't you?
Yeah, I guess I am.
On account of the girl?
Yeah
but what about the horses?
The girl and the horses.
What about Rocha?
Well, he'll have to do
whatever he has to do.
Don't go down there.
- I ain't askin' you to go with me.
- I know you ain't.
Gracias.
They put Mexican blood
in me in that hospital.
So?
So, what does that mean?
About what?
Well, does that mean I'm part Mexican?
How much did they put in you?
They said it was over a liter.
Well,
a liter would make you
at least a half-breed
it don't, does it?
No
No, it don't mean nothin'.
It's just blood.
We don't know where it come from.
You heard about what happened, didn't you?
In the mess hall?
Yeah
yeah
I never thought I'd do that.
You didn't have no choice
he'd have done it to you.
You don't gotta try to make it right.
It is what it is.
- Shit.
- What?
Nothin' just shit
what is it?
I keep thinkin' about ol' blevins,
about how scared he was
you're gonna feel better when you get home.
I don't think so
I ain't blevins
I know you ain't.
I just wonder how much
better off you are than him.
I reckon I'll see you one of these days.
You take care
yeah you take care too.
All right.
I think I'm owed an explanation.
I think the accounts have been
settled quite in your favor.
You have been a great
disappointment to my nephew,
and a considerable expense to me.
No offense, ma'am,
but I've been some inconvenienced myself.
Sit down, please.
The officers were here
once before, you know.
My nephew sent them away
until he was able to have his
own investigation conducted.
He wanted so much
to go on believing in you.
Why didn't he say something to me?
He'd given his word to the comandante.
He should've let me tell my side of it.
You had already lied to him once.
Why should he not assume
you would do so again?
I never lied to him
the affair of the stolen
horse was known here,
even before you arrived.
The thieves were known to be Americans.
When he questioned you about this,
you denied everything.
Why did you buy me out of jail?
I think you know why.
Because of Alejandra.
Yeas
so what'd she have to give in return?
I think
you know that also.
That she won't see me again.
Yeas
you didn't have the right.
You should've left me there.
You would've died
then I'd have died
we're willing that you should have a horse.
I'll trust Esteban to
supervise the selection.
Do you have enough money?
I aim to see her
am I supposed to be surprised?
I'll even give you my permission.
Although that doesn't seem to be a thing
you have ever required.
Her telephone number.
In the end, Mr. Cole,
we all get cured of our sentiments.
Those whom life doesn't cure,
death will
she will not break her word to me.
You will see
yes, ma'am.
We will
Si?
Alejandra?
I knew it would be you.
I have to see you.
I can't
you have to. I'm
coming down there.
No you can't
I won't be here
I go to la purisima in two days.
I'll meet you at the train.
No you can't
my father will have men there.
Alejandra, I love you.
I love you.
You didn't have no right
to make that promise.
Even if they killed me,
you didn't have no right.
And I ain't gonna leave
here until I see you.
Even if it's the last time, I don't care.
Even if they kill me now.
Okay.
I will leave a day early,
tomorrow morning.
I will say that my aunt is ill.
All right.
Okay.
Meet me in /acaftecas
I will be there
Bye.
John
My god, you're beautiful.
Gracias.
It's all my fault.
No. You couldn't have saved us.
You couldn't have saved blevins.
I told my father we were lovers.
- Why?
- Because she threatened me, my aunt.
She said that I must stop seeing
you, or she would tell him.
I couldn't stand for her
to have that power.
She left me no choice.
I told him myself.
I love you so much, I thought
I could make him understand.
But I was so foolish.
It was her arrogance.
I told her I would not be blackmailed
she made me crazy.
But I broke my father's heart.
I broke his heart.
I put you in danger, and you almost died.
He had Armando lock me into my room,
so that I couldn't warn you.
The next morning,
he flew me back to the city.
I thought I would never,
never see you again.
Don't cry.
Alejandra?
I destroyed everything.
I'm gonna make it right.
You can't
well, I will make it right.
Somehow, I will.
You don't understand
what don't I understand?
I didn't know that my
father could stop loving me.
I didn't know he could.
Now I know
What are you doing?
I saw you dead
in a dream
just like the dream I had the
night before we danced together.
It was dawn
men in sarapes stood over you.
And you were dying.
Don't say that.
I want you to marry me
and come to Texas with me.
When I found out you were
in prison, I made a promise.
I know. For my life.
Yeas
I love you.
I'm gonna love you till the day I die.
I believe you.
I swear to god.
No
I cannot do what you ask.
I love you very much, but I cannot.
I have no honor except my promise.
If I lose that too,
then what am I?
No
Mi amor.
Mi corazon.
What do you want?
I come for my horse.
Rawlins's and rblevins's horses too
- I don't have your horses.
- You by god know where they're at, though.
You make bad trouble for yourself.
Mister, I got trouble you
never even heard of
You're free to go.
Okay.
No tiren!
No no tiren!
- Don't shoot!
- No tiren!
No dejen que se escapen.
Si se huyen, matenlos.
Hagan lo que dicen.
I'm going to die.
Yet you just keep talking.
When I die, you die.
Why don't you let me go?
Because you're my hostage.
Stay close, or I swear
to god, I'll shoot you.
I'll shoot you.
Had to come back to my town,
I told you, for my horse.
My head is sick.
I can't ride no more.
You'd be surprised at what you could do.
You're going to die. You're going to die.
We're gonna let god decide about that.
You're not afraid of god?
I'm not afraid of god.
I got no reason to be afraid.
I even got a bone or two to pick with him.
God damn you!
Die, you son of a...
Give me your damn hand right now.
I'm not gonna kill you.
I'm not like you.
Well, go on.
You're free to go
as far as you can
tote that saddle
Ove.
Muchachos
Quieto.
You doing okay?
Thank you.
Vamos I evantate
Howdy.
Howdy. How you doin'?
Wonder if y'all could
tell me what day it is.
It's Thursday.
I mean the date
it's Thanksgiving.
Don't either of y'all
wanna buy a rifle, do ya?
No, I'm not interested.
So I come back across
and was ridin' on the road,
and I run into this man
and he told me that
I had to come see a judge.
There was a problem with the horses.
Your honor, the fact of the matter is
this boy ain't got a lick of proof.
Three different horses
and three different brands on 'em.
Deputy Smith,
do you know what the
trouble with a liar is?
The trouble with a liar is,
he can't remember what he said
I know that's right.
I ain't a liar.
I know that, son.
I know that.
I can't believe that anybody
would've made up a story
like the one you just got done tellin' us.
Can I ask you a personal question?
Yes, sir.
Do you think you'd mind showin' the court
them bullet holes in your leg?
All right.
That's where it come out
that's fine, son. Thank you.
You didn't have no medical attention?
No, sir.
Wasn't none to be had
deputy Smith?
Your honor?
I want you to see that this
boy gets his horses back.
Son, you're free to go.
Thank you.
And the court wants to
thank you for your testimony.
You know, in all the years
I been settin' on this bench,
I heard lots of things
that give me grave doubts
about the human race.
But this ain't one of 'em.
All right.
You can go, boy.
Thank you.
I don't like to bother you,
but they told me this is where you live.
Well, that's all right. They
were right. Come on in.
Thank you.
Pleased to have you.
When I was down there in the penitentiary,
I killed somebody.
I'm sorry to hear that.
He come at me with a knife.
I just happened to get the best of him.
But that keeps bothering me somehow.
Something else, ain't that?
Yes, sir.
Later, I wanted to kill
that other one, too.
That Mexican captain.
Why do you suppose that is?
'Cause I just sat there,
and he walked that boy out there
in the trees and shot him.
I didn't say nothin'.
I didn't say a word.
Would that have done any good?
No, sir.
It don't make it right.
And it never will
it bothered me that you might
think that I'm something special.
I ain't
you know what you strike me as?
One of them people that has a tendency
to be a little tough on themselves.
There's nothing wrong with you, son.
You'll get it sorted out.
I hope so.
If I live.
You'll live, all right.
Lacey once asked me if I thought god
looks out for people.
I guess he does.
/'d say he's just about got fo.
I don't believe we'd
make it a day otherwise.
Thought you might want your old horse back.
Damn, bud.